Let me show you a chart of IC Lobar,
its price performance for the last three-four months,
after that we will discuss the numbers.
IC
Lobar's CF Mr. Gopal Bal Chandan
is present to interact with us. The earnings posted on your screen at one above
today are strong. Hello Gopal ji,
welcome to the program. I
think I will start the sequence of this discussion.
Exactly
with your combined ratio for this quarter, which is around
104.5. In Q2, it was at a
slightly elevated level. And
because the guidance you have given for the full year 25 is
around 10.5,
what are the reasons for such an elevated combined ratio this time and would you like to change this FY25 guidance?
Good morning to you and all our
viewers. If you look at the combined ratio of
IC Lobar, which you rightly said, has been at
104.5 in quarter 2,
but if you look at it, there have been many
flood events in this quarter.  There were
flood events all over the country. There were a
lot of floods in Gujarat, Telangana and North India which were
not there in the last quarter and
if you look at the last quarter of last year also, there were
not so many flood events, hence we have given the
impact of our numbers
separately and we have told that
if you see the combined ratio number, excluding the
impact of these flood events,
then the number comes to 102.6 and if
you see the same number in quarter two of last year, again
excluding the impact of floods, that
number is 102.8, so in that sense, there has actually been a
slight improvement
in our overall combined from 102.8 to 102.6
and your second point was
whether
we are looking to bring any change in our expectation for the year end in terms of combined at 10.5, in short it
is no, at this point of time we are
not making any changes in these  In terms of the
exit combined ratio for quarter four, which we had
talked about earlier at 108.5, we do
not want to make any changes to that at the moment because we
believe that the segments of
businesses that we are underwriting, all the businesses
that we are writing, are clearly
profitable businesses and since we believe at the
end of the year in quarter four, we should be able to kind of stick to the
number of
10.5, okay, okay,
our point taken
means it is quite possible that every year, in the
cut, catastrophic losses will be
a little higher considering I think
floods and rain, I mean, let's assume this, right?
Generally, if you see that a lot of the monsoon
or rainy season is
in quarter two and if
you would have seen last year also, then relatively, the
combined ratio remains slightly elevated in the time period of quarter two,
but for the
rest of the year, I think such businesses will
largely get subsides.  Our combination should kind of
largely get played out. The second
thing is that generally we keep
telling the market that our business is
long term, so whatever outcome you want to see,
you should take it as a long term.
Okay, your point taken means you are
not making any changes in the guarantee of A25, that in itself
reveals your decision.
I will come to some more points. I think let us
talk about the market sentiment and some of the companies which are going through a troubled phase right now. How is the situation in auto right now,
Gopal ji? And how is the situation here this time and
in this running quarter
because the inventory was quite high and the
comments made by some companies are that we are not going very
well in the festival season this time, the
volume is not that much this time. How is the
situation in motor insurance, how has the premium collection been there at this time? This is a
very good
question. So if you see, the beauty of our business is
that we are in multiple business
segments. We are also present in motor,
we also underwrite health, we
underwrite commercial lines.  And at any
point of time, there will
always be a situation in the market where there
is a lot of pressure in some segments, either
due to market competition or
extra demand, due to which it is possible that that
particular segment may not be able to
grow that much, but given that
we are present in other segments as well
and since to that extent, we are able to kind of
significantly grow. Disproportion is
also something that we enact in policies. So, if we
understand relatively late, if the new
vehicle sales remain muted or
grow in single digits, going forward, our
focus is on significant leverage,
our distribution strength,
our use of technology,
our claim servicing capabilities,
because of all of these, I think we will still be able to kind of grow pretty much better than
the market, assumably, if the market becomes quite
disciplined, if the market does
not remain disciplined, so far as pricing is a
concern.  Then even in the past, we have been
a bit cautious at those time periods. I think
we will take a similar approach. If you
look at the time period when new vehicle
sales remain slightly muted, then obviously we
will shift our focus more and more into the
older vehicles. And as you must have seen,
in quarter two also, for example, our
new contribution was flat, but
our old book grew by almost
26 per cent. So, at the overall level,
our growth was 16 per cent while the industry's
growth was around 6 per cent. So, our
beauty has been that I think we will keep looking
for opportunities across different
lines of businesses and wherever we
see profitable segments,
we will underwrite all those segments.
Yes sir, if we look at the health
insurance sector, we
saw a cut of 18 per cent in GST.
How can the policy holder benefit from this? I
think we should actually
wait for that.  I think let's let
the final announcement come through and at that time I
think we will be able to
talk specifically about its
exact impact. But having said that
if you look at health insurance as a
line of business, penetration levels in it are
quite low and that is also another
area where people are thinking that can we
look at making the insurance for more
affordable and there has been a thought that there can be a
reduction in the GST rate, so there
is a huge benefit for the policy holder interest, exactly whether it will be
completely passed through or there will be only
rate reduction at the hands of the policy
holder, but whatever nuances
we will know about, and when the final
announcement is made, then at that time
we can come back and tell you what
exactly will be the impact for the overall
industry and what will be
the impact for you,
Gopal ji. Thank you very much for your participation
in this program.  You participated and you have not made any changes to your outlook regarding this quarter
and the entire financial year.
Thank you very much for discussing all these issues and best of luck to you.